Register of the Vasilii Sergeevich Il'in Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Vasilii Sergeevich Il'in papers
1913-1959
2000C68
Hoover Institution Archives
3 microfilm reels (0.45 linear feet)
Writings, correspondence, printed matter, and photographs, relating to plant physiology and to Russian émigré affairs.
Il'in, Vasilii Sergeevich, 1888-1957
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Biography
V. S. Il'in was a prominent botanist specializing in the biochemistry and physiology of plants. Born in Russia on 17 October 1888, he received his degree in natural science from the University of St. Petersburg in 1912, following which he worked at agricultural research stations in the Voronezh and Ekaterinoslav governments, from 1912 to 1920. In addition to this, from 1917-1920 he was the assistant chancellor of Ekaterinoslav University.
Emigrating to Czechoslovakia, he continued his studies at Prague University, receiving a doctorate in natural science in 1923. Remaining on the staff there, he also became rector of the Russian Free University in Prague. Leaving Czechoslovakia early in the Second World War, he moved to Austria, working from 1941 to 1944 at the University of Vienna, and from 1945 to 1947 at the University of Innsbruck. Turning down invitations from universities in Ecuador, Chile and Peru, he took a position at the National Agricultural Institute in Venezuela, where he remained until 1953. That year, Il'in was appointed professor of plant physiology at the University of Caracas, Venezuela, where he served until his death on 9 August 1957.
Aside from his scientific work, Il'in was an active member of the émigré community, heading charitable institutions wherever he lived and assisting in the passage of Russian displaced persons from Europe to South America after the Second World War.
Chronology
1888 October 17 Born, Poliany, Riazanskaia guberniia, Russia
1912 Degree, Natural Science, University of St. Petersburg
1912-1915 Director, Biological Steppe Station, Voronezhskaia guberniia, Russia
1916-1920 Director, Department of Plant Physiology, Regional Agricultural Experiment Station, Ekaterinoslavskaia guberniia, Russia Professor, Ekaterinoslav University
1920-1940 Professor, Charles University, Prague, Czechoslovakia
1923 Doctoris Rerum Naturalium, Charles University, Prague, Czechoslovakia
1924 Author, Anatomiia i fiziologiia rastenii
1940 Author, Boden und Pflanze
1941-1944 Scientist, Deaprtment of Plant Physiology, University of Vienna, Austria
1945-1947 Scientist, Department of Botany, University of Innsbruck, Austria
1948-1953 Scientist, Agricultural Experiment Station, Department of Soils, Maracay, Venezuela
1953-1957 Professor, Faculty of Agronomy, University of Caracas, Venezuela
1957 August 9 Died, Caracas, Venezuela
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains materials relating to the life and scientific accomplishments of the botanist V. S. Il'in. Materials relating to his biography include numerous obituaries, identity documents and diplomas. His writings include samples of his scientific works, and the subject file and photographic collection illustrate émigré life in Venezuela.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco, as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Plant physiology.; Russia.; Russians--Venezuela.; Venezuela.
- Biographical File, 1938-1959 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Articles, bibliography, calling cards, curriculum vitae, identity papers, programs and other materials arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Correspondence, 1929-1959 (Box 1)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
- Speeches and Writings, 1924-1959 (Box 1-3)
  Scientific articles, studies, and letter to the editor, arranged chronologically by title
- Subject File, 1928-1959 (Box 3)
  Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject
- Photographs, 1950s (Box 4)
  Nearly 100 prints depicting V. S. Il'in, other émigré figures, his scientific work, and Russian churches in Venezuela
- Oversize File, 1913-1948 (Box 4)
  Diplomas and file of materials on Ob'edinenie rossiiskikh emigrantov v Tirole, a Russian émigré association in the Tyrol, Austria
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1938-1959 (Box 1)
  General note
  See also OVERSIZE FILE
  - Articles about or mentioning Il'in (Folder 1: 1)
  - Bibliography (Folder 1: 2)
  - Calling cards (Folder 1: 3)
  - Certificates of appreciation. (Folder 1: 4)
    Includes letters of appreciation from Metropolitan Anastasii, 1946-1947
  - Curriculum vitae (Folder 1: 5)
  - Employment records (Folder 1: 6)
  - Identity documents (Folder 1: 7)
  - Invitations to emigrate to various countries. (Folder 1: 8)
    Includes invitations to teach at universities
  - Membership cards (Folder 1: 9)
  - Programs of conventions listing Il'in's presentations (Folder 1: 10)
  - Scientific reports. (Folder 1: 11)
    Includes activity reports and proposals for further research
  - Miscellany (Folder 1: 12)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1929-1959
  Includes correspondence with Il'in's wife, Nina Ivanovna
  - General
    - General, [1950]-1956 (Folder 1: 13)
    - Scientific correspondence, 1950-1959 (Folder 1: 14)
      Includes invitations to conferences, requests for offprints of articles, and similar correspondence
  - Il'in, Ivan A., 1947-1954 (Folder 1: 15)
    Includes biographical material on Ivan A. Il'in
  - Konstantin, Archimandrite, 1952-1957 (Folder 1: 16)
  - Kutepov, A. P., 1929 (Folder 1: 17)
    See also SUBJECT FILE/Kutepova, L. D.
  - Tolstoy Foundation, 1948 (Folder 1: 18)
  - Turkul, A., 1951-1956 (Folder 1: 19)
  - [Tyrkova]-Williams, Ariadna, 1949 (Folder 1: 20)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1924-1959
  - General, 1949-1955 and undated
    - Field notes (Folder 1: 21)
    - Scientific notes. (Box-folder 2: 1)
      Include calculations, drafts, citations and references to literature and other materials for articles, lectures or research
  - "Bioquímica,", n.d. (Folder 2: 2)
    Holograph
  - "Determinacion...,", n.d. (Folder 2: 3)
    Typescript. Herein are gathered several studies reflecting Il'in's methods of chemical determination
  - "Determinacion colorimetrica de nitratos con alfa-naftilamina,", n.d. (Folder 2: 4)
    Printed copy
  - "Fisiológia vegetal agricola,", n.d. (Folder 2: 5)
  - "Influencia de suelos calcarios sobre el metabolismo en las plantas,", n.d. (Folder 2: 6)
    Typescript
  - "Yield and Chemical Composition of Commercially Fertilized Plants in the Tropics," (Folder 2: 7)
  - Anatomiia i fiziologiia rastenii, 1924 (Folder 2: 8)
  - Boden und Pflanze, 1940 (Folder 2: 9)
  - "Influencia de los abonos sobre la composición química de las plantas. I. Influencia del nitrógeno, fósforo, potasio y calcio sobre el pasto Capim melao," Revista Grancolombiana de Zootecnica, Higiene y Medicina Veterinaria, 1950 January-March (Folder 2: 10)
  - "Determinacion turbimetrica del azufre," Agronomia Tropical, 1951 April-June (Folder 2: 11)
  - "Influencia de los abonos sobre la composición química de las plantas forrajeras," Agro, 1951 June (Folder 2: 12)
  - "Metabolism of Plants Affected with Lime-Induced Chlorosis (Calciose)," Plant and Soil, 1951 July (Folder 2: 13)
  - "Influencia de la sequía sobre algunos de los procesos fisiológicos de las plantas," Revista de la Facultad de Ingenieria Agronomica, 1952 June (Folder 5: 14)
  - "Influencia de abonos fosfatados y nitrogenados sobre la composición química y el rendimiento del pasto Guinea," Agronomia Tropical, 1952 October-December (Folder 2: 15)
  - "Fisiologia vegetal avanzada,"., 1953 (Folder 2: 16)
  - Letter to the editor, 1953 January 25 (Folder 2: 17)
  - "Causes of Death of Plants as a Consequence of Loss of Water: Conservation of Life in Dessicated Tissues," Bulletin of Torrey Botanical Club, 1953 May (Folder 2: 18)
  - "Bioquímica de plantas cloroticas desarrolladas en suelos calcareos," Agronomia Tropical, 1953 October-December (Folder 2: 19)
  - "El aprovechamiento del nitrógeno por la planta," Agro, 1954 January-February (Folder 2: 20)
  - "Nutrición mineral de las plantas," Revista de la Facultad de Agricultura, 1954 February (Box-folder 3: 1)
    Printed copy. Includes abstract (clipping)
  - "Relacion entre suelo y composicion quimica de las plantas forrajeras," Agronomia Tropical, 1955 January-March (Folder 3: 2)
  - El Agua y los Procesos Vitales de la Planta, 1955 September (Folder 3: 3)
  - "Influencia del agua sobre la asimilacion de sales del suelo por las plantas," Revista de la Facultad de Agricultura, 1955 October (Folder 3: 4)
  - "Metabolismo y abonamiento en plantas forrajeras," Revista de la Facultad de Agricultura, 1955 October (Folder 3: 5)
  - "Analyse des plantes et problèmes des fumures minérales," Colloque VIe Congrès International de la Science du Sol, 1956 (Folder 3: 6)
  - "Fisiologia vegetal agricola,"., [1957] (Folder 3: 7)
    See also PHOTOGRAPHS
    Holograph and typescript. Includes partial Russian holograph.
  - "Determination of Nitrogen in Plants Using Hypobromate and Avoiding Distillation," Protoplasma, 1958 (Folder 3: 8)
    Printed copy, and Spanish version, "Metodo del hipobromito para la determinacion de nitrogeno en las plantas," Agronomia Tropical, 1958 January-March
- SUBJECT FILE, 1928-1959
  Correspondence, writings, and printed matter
  - Kutepova, L. D. (Folder 3: 9)
  - Monarchism, Russian (Folder 3: 10)
  - Obitel' Prepodobnogo Iova Pochaevskogo, Munich, Germany (Folder 3: 11)
  - Russians--Venezuela (Folder 3: 12)
  - Russkaia Pravoslavnaia tserkov' (Folder 3: 13)
  - Tserkov' Sv. ap. Petra i Pavla, Maracay, Venezuela. (Folder 3: 14)
  - Miscellany (Folder 3: 15)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1950s (Box 4)
  - 8 prints depicting Vasilii Sergeevich Il'in, his house in Venezuela and tombstone (Folder 4: 1)
  - 9 prints depicting Russian émigré religious, political, military and cultural figures (Folder 4: 2)
  - 6 prints depicting Russian churches in Venezuela, including Tserkov' Sv. ap. Petra i Pavla, Maracay (Folder 4: 3)
  - 12 prints depicting Il'in's work on agricultural experiments in Venezuela. (Folder 4: 4)
    Includes photographs of other researchers
  - Over 50 photographs depicting plant physiology, intended for publication in "Fisiologia vegetal agricola,"., [1957] (Folder 4: 5)
    See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1913-1948
  - Diplomas (Folder 4: 6)
  - Miscellany relating to the activities of the Ob"edinenie rossiiskikh emigrantov v Tirole (Folder 4: 7)